[
    {
        "question": "On a map, what are the lines that run parallel to the equator called?",
        "answer": "Latitude"
    },
    {
        "question": "St. Croix, St. John and St. Thomas are part of what US territory?",
        "answer": "Virgin Islands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the street address of the White House?",
        "answer": "1600 Pennsylvania Avenue"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which English city was once known as Duroliponte?",
        "answer": "Cambridge"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sahti is a type of beer that is traditionally flavored with juniper and it is most likely found in which country?",
        "answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Central American country has a name which translates to English as `The Saviour`?",
        "answer": "El Salvador"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Asian city is the historic waterfront called The Bund?",
        "answer": "Shanghai"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country is May Day the only holiday workers are obliged to be given the day off yet still be paid for it?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state of the United States would you find Fort Knox?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named `Haight Street`?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Stanley Park?",
        "answer": "Vancouver"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Tiergarten?",
        "answer": "Berlin"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Balboa Park?",
        "answer": "San Diego"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Rock Creek Park?",
        "answer": "Washington, D.C."
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city would you find Boboli Gardens?",
        "answer": "Florence"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state advertised `The Greatest Snow on Earth` on its license plates?",
        "answer": "Utah"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Ethiopia`s official language?",
        "answer": "Amharic"
    },
    {
        "question": "`Amharic` is the official language of which African country?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river acts as a natural boundary between the counties of Norfolk and Suffolk?",
        "answer": "River Waveney"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country would you have to visit to see the ruins of Troy?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "question": "As of 2014, which country is the location of the second highest flagpole in the world after Saudi Arabia built a taller one in Jeddah?",
        "answer": "Tajikistan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than English, what is the main language in Guam?",
        "answer": "Chamorro"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are Amsterdam`s buildings so narrow?",
        "answer": "A tax loophole"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Antarctica`s tallest volcano?",
        "answer": "Mount Sidley"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s largest tropical orchid garden?",
        "answer": "Singapore"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Brazilian states are there?",
        "answer": "26"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country holds the record for both the coldest and hottest temperatures in South America?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only Central American country with English as an official language?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European city is regarded as the watch making capital of the world?",
        "answer": "Geneva"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country would you find the city Geneva?",
        "answer": "Switzerland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was a Portuguese moidore?",
        "answer": "A gold coin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Nebraska?",
        "answer": "Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state whose two-letter postal code is two vowels?",
        "answer": "Iowa"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through the city of London?",
        "answer": "Thames"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Washington D.C.?",
        "answer": "Potomac"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Vienna?",
        "answer": "Danube"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which major river is adjacent to Memphis, Egypt?",
        "answer": "The Nile River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the smallest country by area and population?",
        "answer": "Vatican City"
    },
    {
        "question": "What South American country`s name comes from the Latin word for silver?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which county in the United Kingdom is the Glastonbury Festival held?",
        "answer": "Somerset"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states and territories in Australia?",
        "answer": "6 states 10 territories"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state is Helena the capital of?",
        "answer": "Montana"
    },
    {
        "question": "In terms of area, how much bigger is Queensland than the UK?",
        "answer": "Seven times"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thursday Island is located in the Torres Strait off the coast of what country?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is the capital of Northwest Territories in Canada?",
        "answer": "Yellowknife"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in Canada would you find Mount Queen Elizabeth?",
        "answer": "Banff National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "Chisinau is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Moldova"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Moldova?",
        "answer": "Chi\u0219in\u0103u"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Golden Gate Bridge named after?",
        "answer": "Golden Gate was named after the narrow, 300-foot-deep Golden Gate Strait which flows underneath it."
    },
    {
        "question": "What country occupies the southern end of the Arabian Peninsula?",
        "answer": "Yemen"
    }
]